# Erinn Springer

## Personal info

First name: Erinn
Last name: Springer

Web: erinnlspringer.com

GitHub: https://github.com/elspringer

Address: Silbersteinstraße 147, Berlin 12051, Germany

Phone Number: 3126360793

Email address: erinnlspringer@gmail.com

## **Profile**

I am a fullstack web developer with four years experience building and designing products and five years experience in marketing. Over my career I have grown interested in digital rights, online privacy and making technology more inclusive.

# Work experience

Erinn Springer Berlin Germany

## **Web Designer & Developer**

02/2017 - present

**Berlin** Travelogue

- Designed and created the website, travelogue.co.
- Organised and launched events for women only in Berlin.

Teacher & TA at Le Wagon

- · Gave lectures on Rails.
- Helped students with Ruby, Rails, CSS and their final projects that they presented on their demo day.

BlueBuzzard Technology Group Chicago USA

## **Web Developer**

01/2015 - 02/2017

- Wireframed, designed and built Customer Relationship Management (CRM) software to be used for hotel sales and events.
- Built out requests from existing customers and helped move current customers over to the new product features.
- Worked directly with the cofounders of the company.

GoHealth Chicago USA

### **Marketing Coordinator**

07/2009 - 10/2013

- Created and managed all company email, texting, SEO, social media and public relation campaigns.
- Worked on user surveys for PR campaigns.
- Wrote press releases and managed relationships with outside public relation agencies. Also worked with internal team to coordinate projects and postings of media coverage.
- Tracked visits in Omniture from SEO keywords, social media and public relations placements to increase future visits.

## **Education**

Starter School Chicago USA

### Web Development & Design

10/2013 - 05/2014

Went to a nine-month program that taught design, front-end and back-end development, user-experience, and business skills.

Specific languages that I learned include: Ruby on Rails, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, CoffeeScript and more.

Design skills learned include: wireframing, user stories, user testing, copy writing, content management and more.

To read more about the program and my experience at Starter School visit,

## **Education**

http://www.starterschool.com/stories/erinn-barr.

Purdue University West Lafayette USA **Movement & Sports Science** 

08/2005 - 05/2009

Obtained a major in Movement & Sport Science at the Liberal Arts School and a minor in

Organizational Leadership.

# **Skills**

## **Development Languages**

Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS, JS/JQuery, CoffeeScript

#### **Tools**

Google Analytics, Sprout Social, Omniture, Mailchimp, Exact Target, Github

#### **Other Skills**

Writing, Content Marketing, Web Analytics, Email Marketing, SEO, Social Media Optimization